<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">My Application</string>
    <string name="title_item_detail">Item Detail</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main">MainActivity</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="nav_header_title">Indian Freedom Movement</string>
    <string name="nav_header_subtitle">android.studio@android.com</string>
    <string name="nav_header_desc">Navigation header</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <string name="menu_home">Home</string>
    <string name="menu_gallery">Gallery</string>
    <string name="menu_slideshow">Slideshow</string>

    <!--event titles-->
    <string name="event_title_eic">British Invasion</string>
    <string name="event_title_revolt">Revolt of 1857</string>
    <string name="event_title_bengal">Partition of Bengal</string>
    <string name="event_title_inc">Foundation of Indian national Congress</string>
    <string name="event_title_ml">Foundation Of Muslim League</string>
    <string name="event_title_calcutta">Declaration of swaraj</string>
    <string name="event_title_surat">Surat Split</string>
    <string name="event_title_caliph">Khilafat Movement</string>
    <string name="event_title_rowlatt">Rowlatt Act</string>
    <string name="event_title_bagh">Jallianwala Bagh Tragedy</string>
    <string name="event_title_ncm">Non Cooperation Movement</string>
    <string name="event_title_swaraj">Declaration of Poorna Swaraj</string>
    <string name="event_title_cdm">Civil Disobedience movement</string>
    <string name="event_title_ina">Forward Bloc and INA</string>
    <string name="event_title_qim">Quit India Movement</string>
    <string name="event_title_15">Cabinet  Mission Plan</string>
    <string name="event_title_ind">Independence, Partition Of India</string>

    <!--event years-->
    <string name="event_year_eic">1600 \- 1857</string>
    <string name="event_year_revolt">10 May 1857</string>
    <string name="event_year_bengal">28 December 1885</string>
    <string name="event_year_inc">16 October 1905</string>
    <string name="event_year_ml">30 December 1906</string>
    <string name="event_year_calcutta">1906</string>
    <string name="event_year_surat">1907</string>
    <string name="event_year_caliph">19021</string>
    <string name="event_year_rowlatt">18 March 1919</string>
    <string name="event_year_bagh">13 April 1919</string>
    <string name="event_year_ncm">5 September 1920 \- 12 February 1922</string>
    <string name="event_year_swaraj">December 31 1929</string>
    <string name="event_year_cdm">12 March 1930</string>
    <string name="event_year_ina">12 March 1930</string>
    <string name="event_year_qim">1942</string>
    <string name="event_year_15">May 1942</string>
    <string name="event_year_ind">15 August 1947</string>

    <!--event content-->
    <string name="event_content_eic">In <b>1613</b>, during the reign of <u>Jahangir Khan</u>(successor of Akbar) , <u>East India Company</u> entered India to establish a port in Surat. By the early 1700’s it expanded its reach to three more stations and ports namely Madras, Calcutta and  Bombay. The control of these ports were permantly given to the East India Company by the respective rulers during that time. Having more ports than its european counterparts, the East India Company held a monopoly over trade with many of the Indian goods. The only major competitors were the French companies which were only primarily based in Pondicherry.\n\nThe British Empire was benefiting a lot from the East India company trade in India. In <b>1744</b>, it made one-fifths of total imports worth 2 million pounds. It was even able to give a loan of 1 million pound to the British Empire. \n\nAfter the death of <u>Aurangzeb</u>, the Mughal Empire slowly started to disintegrate, many conflicts aroused between the hindus and the mulism in the court which further weakened the power of the successors of Aurangzeb. This resulted in five successful invasions between 1731 and 1761 by <u>Nadir Shah of Persia</u> and <u>Amad Shah Abadali of Afghan</u>. Meanwhile, former Mughal governors and  vassal princes were craving for independent states. During this period, the company to protect its trade helped India kings in exchange of loyalty. But when a war broke out between Great Britain and France in the late 18th century, it began actively invading Indian territories which were primary under the French influence.\n\nThe British rule was formally established after the <b>Battle of Plassey in 1757</b> in Bengal. When British won the Battle of Plassey, thereby establishing the trade monopoly in India. Then after they forced Indian merchants and artisans to sell their products. After establishing a stable rule in Bengal it slowly spread its power by waging wars and offering treaties.\n\n
    </string>
    <string name="event_content_revolt">Right from the beginning of the British rule, there was opposition by many princely states because of policies like subsidiary alliance and doctrine of lapse and battles. These states fought against British but it was concentrated only on a few regions. For the first time since the British rule many kingdoms and states banded together to fight against the British for freedom. This greatest battle is known as the “<b>Revolt of 1857</b>”. \n\nThe revolt began in Meerut on <b>10 May 1957</b> with the introduction of greased cartridges which were supposedly made out of pig and cow/bull fat. This was against the religious beliefs of hindus and muslims sepoys. 85 sepoys in Meerut who protested these cartridges were stripped off from their uniform and sentenced to 10 years of imprisonment. On the next day the other sepoys of the regiment released their fellow soldiers who were imprisoned . They later marched to Red fort and pleaded with the Mughal emperor <u>Bahadur Shah Zafar</u>  to become the leader of the revolt. The rebels captured Delhi from the British. Bahadur shah wrote letters to all chiefs and rulers of India urging them to band together to fight against British regiment. The revolting states are <b>Kanupur</b> led by <u>Nana Sahib</u> and general <u>Tatya Tope</u>, in <b>Lucknow</b> led by <u>Begum Hazat Mahal</u>, in <b>Jhansi</b> by <u>Rani Laxshimi Bai</u>, <b>Bihar</b> by <u>Kunwar singh</u> the son of the jamindar etc.\n\nThe  fierce battle lasted for more than one year thereby depleting the resources from the princely troops whereas the British were supported by other states who were expecting alliance in exchange.  The British captured Delhi on <b>Sept 20, 1857</b>, Bahadur Shah was taken as prisoner and the royal princes were captured and shot dead. Eventhough the revolt of 1857 failed to owerthrow the British rule, it helpes in developing a nationalistic sprit and generated a feeling of oneness among the people of the country which inspries the subsequent stages of freedom of struggle. \n\n
    </string>
    <string name="event_content_bengal">Following the Battle of Buxar in 1765, the Bengal province in British Raj consisted of modern Indian states of Assam, Bihar, Odisha, Jharkhand and West Bengal along with Bangladesh. By 1900 the province had grown too large to be kept under a single administration. East Bengal which had a poor communication network, has been neglected over West Bengal and Bihar. So on <b>16th October 1905</b>  the then viceroy of British, <u>Lord Curzon</u> announced the partition of Bengal by choosing one of the several partition plans. As per Lord Cruzons proposed Partition plan, the modern States of West Bengal, Bihar, Jharkhand and Orissa  would be made into one province named <b>Bengal</b>. Bangladesh, Assam and the North-Eastern States as another province named <b>East Bengal and Assam</b>.\n\nBut this line was drawn in the heart of Bengali speaking nation (making Bengali speaking people a minority in both the provinces) and even creating a bridge on religious grounds. The new Bengal with its captial in Calcutta would consist  Hindu majority population while East Bengal and Assam with its capital in Dhaka would become a Muslim majority. The Congress Party viewed this move as an attempt to “<b>divide and rule</b>” by British, since  Nationalism is prominent in Bengal than the other regions in India. Thus receiving strong opposition from mainly the Bengali Hindus who protested for unity of Bengal, during this time <u>Rabindranath Tagore</u> composed the famous song \’<b>Amar Sonar Bangla</b>\’(English translation: My Golden Bengal”)  which later became the National Anthem of Bangladesh.\n\nThough many Muslims were in support of this movement since Lord Curzo promised economic and social development along with many educational reforms in the new province of East Bengal and Assam, there were still some who opposed this movement.\n\nThese waves of nationalism were carried to many parts of India. As a reaction for the opposition the Bengali Hindus boycotted  British goods and promoted domestic goods (<b>swadeshi</b>) and conducted mass rallies. To show their resolve they ignited British goods. Similar forms of protests aroused in Poona, Bombay, Madras.\n\nThe Indian National Congress also adopted \“<b>Bande Mataram</b>\”  (English translation: “Hail to Thee Mother”) as its national anthem during this time. These words were taken from Anandamath, a popular Bengali novel by <u>Bankim Chandra Chatterjee</u>, and its music composed by <u>Rabindranath Tagore</u>.\n\nAs American historian <u>Will Durant</u> rightly said while describing Lord Curzons decision to Partition Bengal,\“<b>It was in 1905, then, the Indian revolution began.</b>\” As the opposition against British started here they have shaped the character of the future freedom struggle in India. At the same time this plan was successful in creating a communal rift between  Muslims and Hindus in the country and even contributed to the creation of <b>Muslim League in 1906</b>.\n\nFinally in <b>1911</b> the partition was annulled and new provinces were created on the basis on linguist lines rather than religion.\n\n
    </string>
    <string name="event_content_inc"><b>Indian National Congress</b> was founded on <b>28 December 1885</b> by a retired British officer, <u>A.O. Hume</u>. From its formation till the Independence from British it was the most prominent organisation which represented Indians opinion. \n\nThe primary reason behind the foundation of INC was to promote and justify  the governance of British with the help of educated Indians, who were more familiar with the British culture and Ideology. After its formation the <b>early nationalists</b> in the congress were loyal and supportive of British reforms. Appointment of the <b>Public Service Commission</b>, <b>The Indian Councils Act of 1892</b>, <b>Welby Commission</b> were some of the notable achievements by early nationalists. After the <b>Partition of Bengal</b> in <b>1905</b>, the moderate beliefs started losing their popularity and were being replaced with the ideas of <b>swaraj</b> (self rule) and later in the <b>Gandhian Era</b>, the primary objective became <b>poorna swaraj</b> (Complete Independence). \n\nIt was disbanded after the <b>Indian Independence Act 1947</b>. \n\n
    </string>
    <string name="event_content_ml">In the British Raj, Muslims being a minority and lagging behind in economic and educational aspects than the Hindhu majority made the educated muslims seek oppurtunity for uplifiting the muslim communities in India. To add to it the era of Mughal rule (c. 1556–1707), gave Indians Muslims a sense of superiority as well as a sense of separation from the Hindu majority. The partition of Bengal which promised a new province which would have a muslim majority and also social reforms, along with the widespread unrest and protests against this partition plan from Bengali Hindus gave enough momentum for formation of organization which would primarly focusing on well being of Muslims in India.\n\n On <b>December 30, 1906</b>, <u>Aga Khan</u>, the Nawab of Dhaka and <u>Nawab Mohsin-ul-Mulk</u> founded <b>All India Muslim league</b> (which was later popularly refered to as <b>Muslim League</b>) with their primary objective being to safeguard the rights of Indian Muslims and uniting Muslims under a single banner.\n\nInitially, it got great support from British governance since they were promoting the British literature, culture and mainly governance. But after British attacked Ottomon Empire during World War I, Muslim League turned against British and lauched <b>Khilafat Movement</b> to restore the position of the <u>caliph</u>(who was considered the leader of Sunni Muslims) of the Ottoman Caliphate.\n\nThough after world war I , there was some degree of unity between Hindus and Muslims. The relationship broke down after the Khilafat Campaign ended. Then there was a rise of communalism, which resulted in the idea of "<b>Two-Nation Theory</b>" (a belief which says that Hindus and Muslims are separate and can not coexist in a single Nation) becoming popular among muslims.\n\nAfter <b>Lahore Session</b> in <b>1940</b>, under the leadership <u>Muhammad Ali Jinnah</u> the popularity of Muslim league and of a seperate Nation sored among the muslim masses. Which have later contributed directly in the <b>Partition of India</b> and <b>formation of Pakistan</b> in <b>1947</b>.\n\n
    </string>
    <string name="event_content_calcutta">Jalandhar, southeast of Amritsar, in early 1919 after the outbreak of rioting and violence in Amritsar in April, positioned his troops in narroway blocking the entrance to Bagh and ordered 50 soldiers to open fire without heeding any warning to the civilians who were trapped inside the Bagh. The firing continued for 10 to 15 minutes till the ammunition was exhausted. Official reports suggest that about 379 unarmed civilians were killed and 1200 were injured and were provided no further medical assistance.  Dyer claimed that this act was necessary to have widespread order and admitted that he would have continued to fire if there was more ammunition. He was forced to retire but was not reprimed for his actions after this incident. When returned to England he was welcomed as a hero who </string>
    <string name="event_content_surat">During the first few years of Congress leaders were having faith in  British liberalism. Officially( by the British) Congress was recognized as a “<b>microscopic minority</b>”. Naturally a feeling grew within people that the British, despite her promises and assurance was not ready to give any real power to Indians. After <u>Lord Curzon</u> took up the position as Viceroy and passed policies like the <b>Calcutta Corporation Act</b>, the <b>Official Secrets Act</b>, the <b>Indian Universities Act</b> and finally the  Partition of Bengal which made the younger Congress member lose the faith in “<b>Moderate Policy</b>”. /n/nWhich inevitably led to the division of Congress into two camps: the <b>Extremists</b> and the <b>Moderates</b>. Moderates believed in settlement of issues with government by talking and discussing while Extremists wanted self governance(swaraj) and to attain it they were ready to perform riots, strikes and Boycotts./n/nIn <b>1906</b> on <b>Calcutta session</b> the extremists were found powerless against the majority, the Moderates but the open split was tactfully avoided by the elected president <u>Dadabai Naoroji</u> who announced swaraj as a goal of Congress as a strategic plea for extremist ideology. However the extremists were not satisfied and the discord between the two camps deeped. The extremists ideology was growing popular among the masses and party members./n/nIn <b>1907</b> the congress meeting was supposed to be held at Nagpur, but as there were some serious local disputes thus the Working Committee of Congress decided to hold its meeting in Surat instead. The Extremists wanted <u>Lala Lajpat Rai</u> and <u>Bal Gangadhar Tilak</u> as president while the Moderates supported <u>Rash Behari Ghosh</u>./n/n
    </string>
    <string name="event_content_caliph">Before 1930, the  national movement mainly centered with the goal of only having political independence from British, i.e having <b>Home Rule</b> similar to that of other Britain colonies like Canada, Australia, the Irish Free State, Newfoundland, New Zealand, and South Africa. But even after protesting and pleading multiple times British refused to give political and civil freedom.
In <b>December 1928</b>, congress session was held in</string>
    <string name="event_content_rowlatt"><b>Rowlatt Act</b>, official name <b>The Anarchical and Revolutionary Crimes Act of 1919</b> was passed by the <b>Imperial Legislative Council</b> in Delhi on <b>18 March 1919</b>, during World War I.\n\nThis act gives  British the power to  arrest anyone who is supposed to be conspiring  against the British Raj and sentence them upto 2 years without any trial. And any suspects could be detained for an indefinite amount of time. The Indian were not so welcoming of this act since it was oppressing their freedom of speech.\n\n<u>Mahatma Gandhi</u>, one of the many who strongly opposed this Act, organised a \‘<b>hartal</b>\’ (a form of protest through non-violence by stoppage of work and going on hunger strike) on <b>April 6th 1919</b>, realising that constitutional methods of plea were fruitless. <u>Muhammad Ali Jinnah</u>, a member of the <b>All-India Muslim League</b> resigned from the Imperial legislative council in protest against the act. But soon in many parts of India like Bombay, Ahmedabad, Punjab the protest turned violent. Gandhi realising that  people were not ready for non-violence, an integral part of <b>satyagraha</b> suspended the hartal to avoid more grave casualties.\n\nThis Act was later revoked in <b>March 1922</b> after the <b>Jaillanwala Bagh massacre</b> when the British-led troops killed several hundred Indians.\n\n
    </string>
    <string name="event_content_bagh"><b>The Jaillanwala Bagh massacre</b> (also known as the Massacre of Amritsar) incident took place on the afternoon of <b>April 13, 1919</b>. Around 10,000 men, women, and children gathered from nearby villages to celebrate an important Indian festival of Baisakhi, and to conduct a peaceful protest against the arrest of national leaders <u>Satyapal</u> and <u>Saifuddin Kitchlew</u>, despite having a ban being imposed on public gatherings or assemblies at that time.\n\n<u>Reginald Dyer</u> who was posted at Jalandhar, southeast of Amritsar, in early 1919 after the outbreak of rioting and violence in Amritsar in April, positioned his troops in narroway blocking the entrance to Bagh and ordered 50 soldiers to open fire without heeding any warning to the civilians who were trapped inside the Bagh. The firing continued for 10 to 15 minutes till the ammunition was exhausted. Official reports suggest that about 379 unarmed civilians were killed and 1200 were injured and were provided no further medical assistance.  Dyer claimed that this act was necessary to have widespread order and admitted that he would have continued to fire if there was more ammunition. He was forced to retire but was not reprimed for his actions after this incident. When returned to England he was welcomed as a hero who saved the British rule in India mainly by the conservatives and  in the Britain Parliament  by the “<b>House of Lords</b>” and was also awarded with a sword inscribed “<b>Saviour of Punjab</b>”. However he was denounced for his actions by “<b>House of Commoners</b>”.\n\nThis inhumane act from British agitated Indians. Even the Moderates who were partial to British policies have turned against the British after this incident.  <u>Rabindranath Tagore</u> was shocked to the extent that he renounced his British Knighthood as a symbolic act of protest.\n\n
    </string>
    <string name="event_content_ncm">The <b>Non Cooperation Movement</b> was launched on <b>5th September, 1920</b> by <u>Mahatma Gandhi</u> with the plans of obtaining <b>swaraj</b>. After the passing of the <b>Rowlatt Act</b> and the incident of <b>Jallianwala Bagh Massacre</b> Indian National Congress withdrew their support with British reforms. And Muslim League who were also protesting against British for dismemberment of the Ottoman Empire as part of Khailafat movement gave their support to Non Cooperation Movement.\n\nThus soon became widespread throughout the Raj. This movement\'s nature was supposed to be non-violent (<b>ahimsa</b>), and follow the methods like boycotting government runned institutes, foreign goods,  promoting Indian goods, refusing to abide by taxes, withdrawing from their positions from government etc.\n\nFor the first time since the British invasion of India, the whole nation was united which was a total shock for the British authorities.\n\nWhen Gandhi was informed of the <b>Chauri Chaura incident</b> where angry mode set up fire to a police station with 22 police officers trapped inside, Gandhi felt that this movement had steered off the path from <b>Ahimsa</b> thus bringing an end to the Non Cooperation Movement in <b>February 1922</b> .\n\n
    </string>
    <string name="event_content_swaraj">Before 1930, the  national movement mainly centered with the goal of only having political independence from British, i.e having <b>Home Rule</b> similar to that of other Britain colonies like Canada, Australia, the Irish Free State, Newfoundland, New Zealand, and South Africa. But even after protesting and pleading multiple times British refused to give political and civil freedom.
In <b>December 1928</b>, congress session was held in <b>Kolkata</b> and <u>Mohandas Gandhi</u> proposed a resolution that called for the British to grant dominion status to India within two years. After some time Gandhi reduced time to one and to which the British Government failed to give proper response.
Thus, in the annual session of Indian National Congress  held at <b>Lahore</b> on <b>December 1929</b>  under the presidency of <u>Jawaharlal Nehru</u>, passed the resolution of <b>Poorna Swaraj</b> (Complete Independence), which is to be the goal of the national movement.
On <b>December 31 1929</b>, the newly adopted tricolour flag was hoisted on the banks of Ravi river, in <b>Lahore</b>, modern-day Pakistan. And <b>January 26</b> was fixed as <b>Independence Day</b>.
</string>
    <string name="event_content_cdm">Dandi March/nThe Civil Disobedience Movement started with <b>Dandi March</b> (also known as <b>Salt march</b> , <b>Salt Satyagraha</b> and  <b>Dandi Satyagraha</b>),  the 24-day march which lasted from <b>12 March 1930</b> to <b>6 April 1930</b> was led by <u>Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi</u>, it was a direct action campaign to protest against the <b>Britain\’s Salt Act of 1882</b> which gave the monopoly in manufacture and sale of salt to the British. Thus forcing Indian citizens to buy salt from only the British rulers, who charge a heavy salt tax. During the Salt march Gandhi defied the law by picking up a handful of salt which had been formed by the evaporation of sea.\n\nAfter inauguration Civil Disobedience soon broke out all across India. In Tamil Nadu <u>C. Rajgopalchari</u> , in Gujarat <u>Sarojini Naidu</u> led a similar march as the Salt march. Millions of people organized and participated in marches  and boycotts. More than 60,000 people were arrested by the British officials during this period. Even Gandhi himself got arrested on <b>5 May 1930</b>. But the movement carried on.\n\n<h1>First Round Table and Simon Commission</h1>/nWhen the Civil Disobedience movement was still on full swing in colonial India. British government organised the <b>First Round Table Conference</b> at London on <b>12 November 1930</b>. They planned to consider the reforms proposed by <b>Simon Commission, 1927</b>.\n\n This commission was headed by <u>John Simon</u> to review the political situation in colonial India to introduce further reforms and extension of parliamentary democracy. This  was not well received by the nationalists in the first place, there were many protests with the chant “<b>Simon Go Back</b>”. And to top that the government used brutal methods to subdue that protest. And which directly led to the death of <u>Lala Lajpat Raj</u> who was beaten severely in a lathi charge in Lahore and then succumbed to death.\n\n<b>Indian National Congress</b> which was involved with the Civil Disobedience Movement boycotted the conference. But it was attendend by some representives which included <b>Muslim League</b> and <b>Hindu Mahasaba</b>. But the conference resulted in no conclusion cause of lack of participation of many key figures in colonial India.\n\nSecond Table Conference and Gandhi-irwin pact/n</string>
    <string name="event_content_ina">Forward Bloc and INA</string>
    <string name="event_content_qim">Before 1930, the  national movement mainly centered with the goal of only having political independence from British, i.e having <b>Home Rule</b> similar to that of other Britain colonies like Canada, Australia, the Irish Free State, Newfoundland, New Zealand, and South Africa. But even after protesting and pleading multiple times British refused to give political and civil freedom.
In <b>December 1928</b>, congress session was held in</string>
    <string name="event_content_15">Before 1930, the  national movement mainly centered with the goal of only having political independence from British, i.e having <b>Home Rule</b> similar to that of other Britain colonies like Canada, Australia, the Irish Free State, Newfoundland, New Zealand, and South Africa. But even after protesting and pleading multiple times British refused to give political and civil freedom.
In <b>December 1928</b>, congress session was held in</string>
    <string name="event_content_ind">Before 1930, the  national movement mainly centered with the goal of only having political independence from British, i.e having <b>Home Rule</b> similar to that of other Britain colonies like Canada, Australia, the Irish Free State, Newfoundland, New Zealand, and South Africa. But even after protesting and pleading multiple times British refused to give political and civil freedom.
In <b>December 1928</b>, congress session was held in</string>

    <string name="title_event_list">Events</string>
    <string name="title_event_detail">Event Detail</string>
    <string name="text_size_decrease_error">Can\'t decrease the size</string>
    <string name="text_size_increase_error">cant increase size</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>


    <string name="about_content">Indian Freedom Movement was made as the project for internship under APSSDC (Andhra Pradesh State Skills Development Corporation) which was conducted between 21 March 2020, 28 August 2020. \n\nThis App is built on java in Android Studio.  All the artwork is original and created using inkscape, the artwork is licensed under creative commons, you can download the source from Github link.\n\nIf there is any misinformation, or technical bug please report it to the following mail: abcd@gmail.com.\n\nYou can follow me(developer) at: link 1\n\n
    </string>
</resources>